<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Academic on Yuchen Hui (Xi)</title><link>https://yuchenhui22314.github.io/hugo-stack-test/tags/academic/</link><description>Recent content in Academic on Yuchen Hui (Xi)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yuchenhui22314.github.io/hugo-stack-test/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biography</title><link>https://yuchenhui22314.github.io/hugo-stack-test/p/biography/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yuchenhui22314.github.io/hugo-stack-test/p/biography/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://yuchenhui22314.github.io/hugo-stack-test/p/biography/fall.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Biography" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am 惠语辰, a Ph.D. student in Computer Science at the &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.umontreal.ca/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;University of Montreal&lt;/a&gt;. I am a member of the UdeM NLP (Natural Language Processing) Lab &lt;a class="link" href="http://rali.iro.umontreal.ca/rali/?q=en/accueil" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;RALI&lt;/a&gt; (Recherche Appliquée en Linguistique Informatique). I am fortunate to be advised by Professor &lt;a class="link" href="https://recherche.umontreal.ca/english/our-researchers/professors-directory/researcher/is/in14444/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Jian-Yun Nie&lt;/a&gt;. My doctoral research focuses on enhancing the generalization capability of neural retrieval models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before beginning my doctoral studies, I obtained both my Bachelor’s and Master’s degrees from l&amp;rsquo;Université de Montréal, majoring in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence. My &lt;a class="link" href="https://umontreal.scholaris.ca/items/0f1f66df-09fe-46b2-b45f-b8f53015e29f" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Master’s thesis&lt;/a&gt; focused on adaptive personalization in conversational search systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent my childhood and adolescence in Nanjing, China, and graduated from &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nanjing_Jinling_High_School" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Jin Ling High School&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my spare time, I enjoy playing badminton (see my &lt;a class="link" href="https://badmintoncanada.tournamentsoftware.com/player-profile/55194fbb-9349-4acd-adad-ff52aee21339" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Badminton Canada profile&lt;/a&gt;) and Chinese chess. I also enjoy reading and writing in Chinese. My reading interests primarily include science fiction and history. In terms of writing, I regularly record my dreams and personal reflections. One of the goals of this website is to archive some of these writings in the form of blog posts. Music is another of my passions; I particularly enjoy listening to music, especially ballet music (e.g., Nutcracker, Swan Lake, Giselle, Don Quixote, Paquita, etc.) and Chinese pop music (e.g. 许嵩).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can speak Mandarin, English, and French, so please feel free to reach out in any of these languages! You can contact me via email at yuchen[dot]hui[at]umontreal[dot]ca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also a weather enthusiast and often find myself excited by the occurrence of distinctive weather events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know how to pronounce my name correctly? ; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>